Kishan B

Location: Chennai **Phone**: 9003078932

E-mail: kishancs46@gmail.com

Summary

A curious programmer, having 4.5+ years of experience in full stack web app development using Flex, J2EE and Oracle DB for financial service applications.

Technical Skills

Languages : Java, Actionscript, Swift, Objective-C, Ruby

JS Frameworks : Polymer, Ionic, Jquery, Angular JS, Bootstrap, Foundation

Version Control : SVN, GIT

Databases : MySQL, Oracle, Mongo DB

WAS : Apache Tomcat, Weblogic & Google App Engine

J2EE Framework: Web Services (JAX-WS, JAX-RS), EJB, Spring & Hibernate

Others : IOS Programming, Android Programming

Certifications

- Intro to "Hadoop and MapReduce" by Cloudera via Udacity.
- Nanodegree on "Ruby programming" from Udacity.
- "Algorithmic Toolbox" from UC San Diego via Coursera.

Self-Learning Projects

- OFSSLibrarian using Java 8 used by librarians in our company.
- Nexuslighting.in A LED light shopping site.
- A ruby gem Colorizr A simple gem to colorize terminal output.
- An iOS project showing real time ranking of users based their post likes.

Professional Experience

Place : Oracle Financial Software Services Limited

Designation : Staff Consultant

Duration : Sep 2011 – To Date

Job profile : Full stack programmer, Manual Tester

Tech Stack : J2EE, Flex and Oracle DB

Achievement: Received "We applaud" cash rewards for two years in a row.

Came 2nd in the top 10 resources list during my training. Client appreciation mails for my contributions to Trade link **Project Name:** Trade Link

Duration: March 2013 – Till Date

Client : CITI Bank

Team Size : 8

Role : Developer

Technology: Flex, Java, EJB, Spring, Hibernate, JAX-WS, Weblogic and

Oracle DB.

Description:

Primarily provides web services (JAX-WS) for price request creation and deal booking processes. The webservice resides on citibank's TPS2 and Blotter application targeting marketing consumers. This also provides screens for dealers to process financial instruments created by marketing using webservices.

Responsibilities:

Development of the following modules in the application

- Writing web services in TPS2 & TPS2-Blotter application.
- Screen development
 - Ideas screen This is a core screen of the entire application which received heavy client accolades.
 - Ticker Upload screen FI New Issue screen.
 - MLI Pricer screen.
 - EAED Blotter screen.

Project Name: TPS2 (Blotter)

Duration : Oct 2012 – Feb 2013

Client : CITI Bank

Team Size : 2

Role : Developer

Technology: Flex, Java, EJB, Spring, Hibernate, JAX-WS, Weblogic and

Oracle DB.

Description:

This Enhancement seeks to automate existing dealer's OTC pricing enquiry process, by providing a structured and centralized approach in acquiring OTC pricing with the counterparties. The proposed change will see integration of pricing amongst two main products from the Equity Desk front, incorporating OTC request & response automation by leveraging on existing implementation of ELN Auto-Pricer in TPS2 to simplify the current manual and laborious approach of pricing requests

Responsibilities:

- Development of OTC Autopricer.
- Manual testing (UT and ST) of OTC autopricer.
- Onsite coordination with support activities.

Project Name: Treasury Product System (TPS2)

Duration : Apr 2012 – Sep 2012

Client : CITI Bank

Team Size : 8 Role : Tester

Description:

The TPS2 is a reverse engineering of existing Treasury Product System (TPS) application TPS is a back office trade processing application. TPS2 is capable of handling FX Options, Equity Linked Notes (ELN), Structured Products (SP), Over the Counter (OTC) options and swaps. The TPS features include Deal booking, Deal Enquiry, Static Maintenances, Deal Events (like Knock-in, Knock-out, Exercise, and Expire), and Accounting module. The objective of reverse engineering existing TPS application is to

- Build a robust, volume insensitive and provide high performance application
- Reduce the TAT for new product introduction
- o Customize and Rollout in different branches in multiple time zones.

Improve the user experience

Responsibilities:

 I was deployed in testing team for understanding the functionalities of the OTC (Over the counter) Module in the TPS2 application.

Project Name: OFSS Project Tracker for Leads (OPTL)

Duration : Nov 2011 – Mar 2012

Client: Training Project

Team Size : 4

Role: Designer and developer

Technology: HTML, Javascript, DWR, weblogic and Oracle DB.

Description:

OPTL (OFSS Project Tracker for Leads) is a tracking system for tracking the tasks, risk and activities involved in a project. Currently there are various Tracking and Monitoring tools available for Managers. But OPTL is targeted specifically for the Team Leads and Project Leads who are involved in handling teams and project modules. This tool will be used to track and monitor their project team and modules in better way and thus optimize the time and resource utility.

The major drivers for the OPTL application are

- To automate the tracking process currently used by the leads.
- To bring in all the tasks, risks and activities associated to a developer under one roof.
- To give the lead a list of developers who are currently available for him to bring into his team.
- To have an easy maintainability of all the tasks, risks and activities associated with the developer.

Responsibilities:

- Developed the admin screen for the OPTL application with my colleagues.
- Coordinated and Co-operated with fellow team mates and other teams and also with Mentors.
- Have done testing and enhancement based on comments and feedback from Mentors

Educational Qualification

- B.E in Computer Science and Engineering from St. Peter's Engineering College, Avadi, Chennai, Anna University, Tamilnadu with 72%.
- Higher Secondary Education (2007) in CBSE from Vivekananda vidyalaya with 73%.
- SSC (2005) in CBSE from Vivekananda vidyalaya with 73%.

Extra Curricular Activities

• ERT (Emergency Response Team) Member.

Declaration

I declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my Knowledge.

Kishan B